Lucas Rizoli

<u>lucas@lucasrizoli.com</u> +1 647 520 7887 https://lucasrizoli.com/

An effective User Experience Researcher with years of experience generating insights and motivating change to better products and processes. Advocated for the users on web, mobile, and in entertainment software projects, small and large; collaborated across disciplines and organizations to achieve success within and without.

Selected Experience

UX Research Project Manager, Ubisoft Toronto

2016 - 2020

- Directed UX research for multi-million-dollar software titles *Starlink*: *Battle for Atlas* and *Far Cry 6* in all aspects: needs-gathering, strategy, schedule, budget, methodology, recruitment, and reporting.
- Championed users, working closely with experts, design, art, and production to exceed existing standards. Advocated for accessibility, leading early feature design and requirements.
- Worked with business, marketing, direction, and more to identify goals and opportunities.
- Developed new research methodologies and processes to address stakeholders' needs: generative and evaluative studies, user journeys, narrative tests, wayfinding, testing with children, toy ergonomics.
- Built processes, templates, and documentation to make work clearer, faster, more effective.
- Coached analysts, moderators, and designers on UX, reporting, and usability to improve study and report quality, to communicate clearly, build rapport, manage time and expectations.
- Organized in-depth summary studies and discussions of existing research to address design needs early. Facilitated post-study action on research insights; integrated changing needs into research plans.
- Coordinated UX research and development across many teams in studios across the world. Furthered access & understanding of UX research across the organization.

2014 - 2016

UX Research Analyst, Ubisoft Toronto

- Conducted over a hundred studies, often from planning, design, recruitment, technical set-up, to analysis and reporting. Produced results with direct and sizable impacts on many products.
- Analyzed and synthesized insights from a variety of qualitative and quantitative data from telemetry, video, eye-tracking, individual and group interviews, questionnaires, and more.
- Ran usability studies, think-aloud, heuristic evaluations, cognitive walkthroughs, card sorts, focus groups, qualitative coding, RITE, appreciation studies and many more.
- Established new and improved standards and tools for reporting, statistical analyses, prioritization, and KPIs. Helped improve research processes with experience, research, coaching, and iteration.
- Transformed reporting processes to present results in 3 days—where 7 previously.
- Trained many across the organization on user-centred design and research processes.
- Worked with developers and production to plan work, further tests, and long-term goals.
- Consulted with designers and researchers to better understand users and their needs, to
 prototype and test iteratively, and to use existing knowledge to maximize effectiveness of
 their work.

 Analyst for more than 25 software titles and franchises for PlayStation/Xbox/Switch, PC, and mobile phones, including Assassin's Creed, Watch Dogs, Far Cry, The Crew, The Division, Super Mario + Rabbids, Ghost Recon, South Park, Care Bears, and various unannounced titles.

2013 - 2014

Developer/Analyst, Massive Insights

• Prepared, synthesized, visualized, and analyzed large data using Tableau, Excel, and Python.

2012 - 2013

Web Developer, University of Toronto Scarborough

- Carried out targeted usability and accessibility testing of websites and how results were used.
- Worked with staff, faculty, and students to organize an information architecture to meet institutional and user needs.
- Introduced and integrated new coding practices and tools to better consistency and productivity.

2011 - 2012

Web & Mobile App Developer, LoyaltyOne

- Designed, developed, and debugged mobile apps from UX to APIs, integrating various teams.
- Used analytics and logs to study behavior, track effects of changes to websites and apps.
- Wrote technical and business requirements, bug reports, unit tests, technical documentation, wireframes, and mock-ups for varied audiences.
- Researched, experimented, and reported on new technology and practices to make recommendations and determine product strategy.
- Developed websites with HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, PHP, JSP.

Education

MSc in Computer Science, University of British Columbia, Vancouver

2006 - 2010

- Thesis project: A multimedia interface for facilitating comparisons of opinions. Published and presented at the International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces, 2009.
- Courses included HCI/UI, Natural Language Processing, Information Visualization, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Scientific Journalism, Semantics (Linguistics), and English Grammar.
- Teaching Assistant for courses on Human–Computer Interaction and Computing Ethics & Society.

BCmp (Honours) in Cognitive Science, Queen's University, Kingston

2002 - 2006

Activities

- User Research Mentor, IGDA Games Research and User Experience Special Interest Group
- Co-founder of both Undistinguished Lecture Series at UBC and Perch Lecture Group (Toronto)
- Clear, capable, and confident speaker.